Jackson Beytebiere

206-780-5357 | jacksongrowson@gmail.com Website | Github | Blog | Linkedin

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in React and Redux. Possess strong skills in team-building and project management that help tech companies write efficient and clean code. Communicative and analytical. Engages with the public and community through open source projects and community service. Over a year of HTML, Javascript and CSS experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript ES6, React, Redux, R, Matlab

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

People Pages - Website | Github

Social media website similar to Facebook for connecting with friends

- Sleek CSS and HTML code with a dark-theme implemented
- Designed modular front end and built reusable components with React and Javascript ES6
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side to decrease server-side
- Integrated Redux to manage state with a single source of truth boosting client-side performance
- Implemented Firebase Cloud Storage to store user-generated content making for an easy way to upload images, decreasing client-side operations

StockApp - Website | Github

Stock portfolio tracker with custom watchlists

- Constructed an interactive and easy to navigate UI designed using React, increasing server-side operational performance
- Implemented React Router to build client-side routing, balancing server to client responsibilities
- Created a RESTful API using Ruby on Rails to keep stock and user information and grow app productivity
- Communicated intended changes to design and structure of code with teammate prior to execution to reduce syntactical errors

DavisList - Website | Github

Craigslist-inspired site for making posts in a certain area or category

- Extensive custom CSS code resulting in an appealing website
- Used Ruby-on-Rails to create a full-stack website
- Took advantage of cookies to store client information with no extra burden on the server and to lighten the load on the server's memory

EXPERIENCE

San Carlos Restaurant

Bainbridge Island, Washington 08/2017 - 08/2020

Line Cook

- Directed the kitchen team to create quality meals efficiently resulting in faster service, cutting wait times by an average of 15%
- Ensured ingredients were stocked and food prepared each day reducing waste by 100s of dollars

Tri-beta Tutoring Science Tutor

Seattle, Washington 09/2016 - 02/2019

Explained scientific concepts in easy to understand language to 100+ college freshmen students

- Broke down complex problems to individual learning levels helping students pass final exams
- Achieved 98% pass rate of students tutored compared to the 80% pass rate of untutored students

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Seattle, Washington 08/2020 - 12/2020

Full Stack Web Development, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

University of Washington Bachelor of Science

Seattle, Washington 02/2019